Trust everyone... But always cut the cards.
Rounders is a drama, crime film directed by John Dahl.
Poker addict Mike McDermott knows the game inside out, but loses his money
one night in a game to Russian-American gangster Teddy KGB.
Promising his partner Jo he'll give up, he meets up with best friend Lester 'Worm' Murphy,
just out of prison and owing lots of money to the wrong kind of people.
McDermott becomes his co-guarantor and now there's only one way to
raise the money, the pair have to get back into the game.
Mike McDermott, played by Matt Damon.
Lester 'Worm' Murphy, played by Edward Norton.
Joey Knish, played by John Turturro.
Jo, played by Gretchen Mol.
Teddy KGB, played by John Malkovich.
Petra, played by Famke Janssen.
Rounders is a 1998 American drama film about the underground world of high-stakes
poker, directed by John Dahl and starring Matt Damon and Edward Norton.
The story follows two friends who need to win at
high-stakes poker to quickly pay off a large debt.
The term "rounder" refers to a person traveling around from
city to city seeking high-stakes card games.
Rounders opened to mixed reviews and was
moderately successful at the box office.
Following the poker boom in the early 2000s, the film became a cult hit.
A novelization of the film was written by Kevin
Canty and released by Hyperion Books.
The film explores themes of new york city, friendship, casino, poker, gambling.
The tone is dark and emotional.